### Egor Philippov FULL STACK ENGINEER

W: egorphilippov.me
G: github.com/lone-cloud
E: egor@nidratech.com

### **ABOUT**

A passionate technology professional with the ability to work on all parts of an application, be it on the server, browser or mobile.

Highly adaptable, innovative and articulate communicator specializing in building world class web applications. Proficient with Shopify, Stripe, Postmark and AuthO platforms.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **PANASONIC**

### SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

Remote Apr 2020 - Present

- Systems design, full stack development and some dev-ops for yohana.com and portal.yohana.com
- Full stack development using Next.js (TypeScript) of a number of new web applications. Backend development of gRPC microservices using Micronaut (Kotlin framework).
- Establishing and enforcing best software development practices, enforcing accessibility guidelines, running interviews, CI/CD implementation and general build + deployment automation.
- Wrote and automated the automatic re-publishing of a library for sharing the protobuf typings between Kotlin and TypeScript projects.
- Implemented rich, HTML-based, litmus-tested email templates and a related client library.

#### **GOOGLE**

### **FULL STACK ENGINEER**

Remote & Palo Alto, US Oct 2016 - Apr 2020  Full stack development of various various enterprise applications for Google Store and Nest including enterprise.nest.com, <u>hvac.nest.com</u> and <u>home.nest.com/login</u>

### NIDRATECH LTD

### **TECHNICAL LEAD**

Vancouver, Canada Aug 2015 - Present Lead the development of several web, mobile and browser applications:

- <u>score.restaurant</u> A web app for searching the rankings of restaurants based on health inspection reports.
- <u>huegasm.com</u> A browser extension, web and mobile app for controlling Philips Hue lights and synchronizing them with the beat of your music.

## ABSOLUTE SOFTWARE

Vancouver, Canada Jan 2014 - Oct 2016

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Full stack development using Java EE and Ember.js of enterprise web applications for remote management of company owned mobile devices.

# **OPENBET TECHNOLOGIES**

Burnaby, Canada Aug 2012 - Jan 2014

### JUNIOR – INTERMEDIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Full stack development using TCL and Backbone.js of an online casino and sports betting portal for a Canadian casino at playnow.com
- Special emphasis was put into database performance and high concurrency.

### SAP INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Vancouver, Canada Sept 2009 - Sept 2010 • Java development of installation software for a business intelligence suite (Crystal Reports).

### **EDUCATION**

# SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

Burnaby, Canada Sept 2008 - Apr 2012

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTING SCIENCE

• Concentration in distributed systems.